wikiloc.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy policy - Wikiloc

_May 2018_

The website available at [https://www.wikiloc.com](https://www.wikiloc.com/), including any of its subdomains or sections (the " **Website** ") and any of the mobile applications linked to the Website (" **Applications** ") are operated by Wikiloc Outdoor, S.L. (" **Wikiloc** "). 

This Privacy Policy deals with the processing of Website and Applications users’ personal data by Wikiloc as part of the services provided through the Website and the Applications (" **Services** "). 

By accessing and using the Website or the download or use of the Applications, it is understood that the user has read and agreed to the terms of this Privacy Policy. The date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy refers to the latest update of this Privacy Policy, which will be applicable from the date of publication. Thus Wikiloc recommends that this Privacy Policy is reviewed on a regular basis by the user. 

Some of the Services provided through the Website or of the Applications may be subject to specific privacy policies that will complement or, if in conflict with this Privacy Policy, supersede the terms of this Privacy Policy. The user will accept any specific privacy policies that may apply before the provision of such service commences. 

Additionally, access and use of the Website, and download and use of the Applications and Services are subject to the Terms of Use. 

##  1\. PERSONAL DATA FILES, PURPOSES OF THE PROCESSING AND TYPES OF PERSONAL DATA 

Wikiloc process personal data collected through the Services for the purpose of managing the Website and the Applications and also for providing or improving the provision of Services, including emailing about the Service, the trails requested by the user, the content accessed by the User or with information about the Service, the Website or Applications. 

Personal data that can be collected at the time of registration of the user or afterwards, are the following: 

  * Nickname (mandatory). 
  * Password (mandatory). 
  * Email address (mandatory). 
  * Home page or weblog. 
  * About user (description). 
  * Photo. 
  * Activities of interest. 
  * User’s location. 
  * Units of measure. 
  * Privacy settings. 

Wikiloc does not collect the age or the date of birth of its users. Accordingly, there is no specific processing of minor’s personal data. Wikiloc is only addressed to users above 16 years old. If the user is under age he should not register on Wikiloc. 

Additionally, users may upload their trails through the Services, including geographical information, date, means of transport, trail duration, difficulty level, pictures taken, videos recorded and any comments they deem appropriate. Users may also identify their favorite trails, and keep track of other users’ activities. 

If the user wishes to use the Services which include location features, such as the recording of a trail or of a point of interest or the navigation through a downloaded trail, the Services may imply the processing of the location of the user, which will be used for the purposes stablished hereunder and to allow or improve the Service. 

Likewise, when the user uses the Application for Garmin Connect IQ, the Application will collect and retain the anonymous identifier of the Garmin device and associate it with the account of the user in the Services, in order to maintain the session and avoid the introduction of user and password in the uninstalls or updates of the Application. The user may at any time unlink and eliminate such association through the profile settings. 

Any information received from Wikiloc in the Contact form available in the Website will only be used with the purpose of solving queries, suggestions or claims sent from the users in the Website. Also, personal data included on the comments in the blog of wikiloc.com will only be used for the purpose of answering those comments when necessary. 

The legal basis for processing the user’s personal data is the contractual relationship for the rendering of Services or when appropriate, the fulfillment of the user’s request, as well as the legitimate interest of Wikiloc in offering the Services in the different channels where the trails may be published and in informing about news on the Service offered to users registered that have not rejected the receipt of this information. 

Personal data will be stored during the period required for the compliance with the purpose for which the data was collected and, afterwards, during the periods required by applicable regulations. When a user’s application for registration is not validated within 7 days, the user’s data will be erased. 

## 2\. USE OF COOKIES

The Website uses cookies to facilitate and customize user navigation through the Website. 

A cookie is a small piece of text that web sites you visit send to the browser to allow the web site to remember information about your visit. Wikiloc uses cookies to remember preferences such as your language, increasing the relevancy of the ads you see, count the number of visitors on pages or allow you to log in to download content and access your personal space. Wikiloc uses cookies to remember preferences such as your language, increasing the relevancy of the ads you see, count the number of visitors on pages or allow you to log in to download content and access your personal space.

Wikiloc cookies help provide additional functionality to the Website and help Wikiloc analyze the Website usage more accurately. For instance, the Website may set a cookie on the user’s browser that prevents the user from having to remember and then enter a password more than once during a visit to the Website. On most web browsers, users will find a "help" section on the toolbar. Wikiloc refers to this section for information on how to receive notification when receiving a new cookie and how to turn cookies off. Wikiloc informs users that allowing the use of cookies by their browser will permit users to take advantage of some of the Website's features. 

### What kind of cookies uses Wikiloc?

We use our own cookies with the sole purpose of providing you an enjoyable navigation such as remembering the language in which you prefer to browse the site or session information to allow you access your personal space on Wikiloc. 

Wikiloc does not use own cookies with advertising purposes, nor to associate browsing data with individuals that have not been previously identified. 

### We also use third party cookies, Google Analytics and Google AdSense

Third parties advertising on the Website could use cookies or ‘web beacons’ for which Wikiloc would not be responsible and which would not be governed by this Privacy Policy, so it is the responsibility of the user to set the options in his/her browser in order that cookies are only used according to his/her own preferences. 

Google Analytics cookies are statistical means to measure web traffic to help us learn what pages are most visited and allow us to identify which parts of the site we need to improve. Google has detailed and updated information on these cookies: [http://www.google.es/intl/es/analytics/privacyoverview.html](https://www.google.es/intl/es/analytics/privacyoverview.html)

We also use Google AdSense to display ads on some pages at Wikiloc. Google AdSense cookies have the primary objective of showing ads relevant and of interest to the user. For further information on AdSense cookies visit: <https://www.google.com/intl/es/policies/technologies/ads/>

This Website also has access to the IP address with which each user accesses the Website (including any access from the Applications). The IP address with which each user accesses the Website may be different each time. Additionally, different users can share a single IP address. 

Even though Wikiloc does not and will not attempt to associate the IP address with specific individuals, accessing IP addresses could be regarded as a processing of personal data given the possibility to identify the individual to which an IP address is associated (more a theoretical than an actual possibility). Consequently, according to the applicable data protection law, this Privacy Policy will apply. 

### How to disable cookies in your browser

Browsers allow you to configure the acceptance or rejection of cookies. These settings depend on each browser but you can usually find them in the "Options" or " Preferences" on the browser’s main menu. [For further information, click here.](https://www.agpd.es/portalwebAGPD/CanalDelCiudadano/protegetuprivacidad/index-iden-idphp.php)

##  3\. COMMUNICATION OF PERSONAL DATA 

The way the Services work implies that part of the information provided by the users will be available to other Website users through the Website or the Applications. Such other users with access to that information could be located anywhere in the world. Users should refrain from providing information during the registration process which they do not want to make available to other users. Providing such additional information is not a requirement for using the Services. Users may, at any time, modify or delete this information (except for the nickname and email address) by accessing to "Your settings page". However, Wikiloc will not publish users email unless they mark it as "public" during the registration process or afterwards. 

Additionally, users can mark the trails that they upload to the Services as "public" or "private". By default, trails are marked as public and are available to other users. During the uploading process or at any time afterwards users will be able to modify this attribute for each of their trails by editing the trail properties. 

Any user publishing within the Website or the Applications personal information of third parties guarantees that he/she has previously obtained such third parties’ consent. 

Users can also invite others to visualize their location and current trail on a map. The User will be notified when someone has accepted the invitation to follow their trail and will have the ability to stop sharing this information at anytime. Wikiloc does not assume any liability in relation to the risks associated with allowing others access to the User’s location. Wikiloc does not assume any liability in relation to the processing of users’ personal data by third parties’ platforms through which the user shares the invitation. 

The Services offered through the Website and the Application implies that public trails and certain information related to them are shared with Google Inc. and Google group companies, to be be displayed through the Google Earth viewer, which will be processed according with Google Inc. privacy policy. Furthermore, in order for the Services to allow trails to be viewed in relief, essential function for the trails to be more accessible to the rest of users, certain public routes selected according to its qualities, may be published by Wikiloc for viewing on Google Earth, unless the user disactivates this option on his account settings 

Wikiloc also offers users the possibility to show their trails on Facebook. In order to do this, Wikiloc and Facebook must share user’s personal data. Wikiloc does not assume any liability in relation to the processing of user’s personal data by Facebook. 

Wikiloc runs a forum in which users request help or make suggestions and also a internet blog in which users may make comments. Personal data provided by the users in this forum or blog is subject to the provisions of this Privacy Policy, and is available to other users of the forum or blog. 

The blog available on Wikiloc.com is hosted by blogger.com, whom will store the comments made in the blog, according to its own privacy policy. 

Some of the above entities may be located outside the European Economic Area, in countries that do not have equivalent data protection legislation, although proper guaranties will be required to assure that your personal data is protected at any time according to applicable regulations. 

Sometimes Wikiloc may have to share certain information in order to accomplish legal obligations, however, the information will be shared according to legal requirements and guaranties established in data protection legislation. 

Wikiloc also offers users the possibility of sharing their routes through social networks. In such cases, when clicking the corresponding button, the user will enter the selected network and will be sharing the routes according to the terms of use and data protection policies on that social network. 

##  4\. EXERCISE OF RIGHTS 

Wikiloc guarantees the exercise of the rights of access, rectification, suppression, limitation and portability to the processor, as established by applicable regulations. 

At any time, any data subject who intends to exercise any such rights in connection with personal data will be able to do by accessing the Website, section “My Account”. 

Also, any subject interested on exercising any such rights in connection with personal data should contact Wikiloc at the address of the data controller included in this Privacy Policy or the following email address: [support@wikiloc.com](mailto:support@wikiloc.com)., including in the subject a clear reference to the right he/she intends to exercise and addressing the email to the attention of Wikiloc. 

Wikiloc shall answer the request in all cases, regardless of whether or not there is personal data of the particular data subject within its personal data filing systems. If the request does not comply with the requirements above, Wikiloc shall request the data subject to provide the necessary additional information. In any case, the user has the right to claim to the Spanish Data Protection Agency (Agencia Española de Protección de Datos, AEPD), at www.agpd.es. 

##  5\. GENERAL AND CONTACT INFORMATION 

The processing of personal data by Wikiloc is governed by Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data. 

Wikiloc, the data controller, is registered in the Commercial Registry of Girona, Volume 2709, sheet 156, page number GI 47726, with tax number B-55022115 and its offices are located at Parc Cientific i Tecnologic of the Universitat de Girona, -Giroempren building - Office A2-02, C/Pic de Peguera, 11, Girona, Spain. Wikiloc may be contacted in the following email address: [support@wikiloc.com](mailto:support@wikiloc.com).
